joblift.com 2019-01-03

# Privacy policy

### General information

Users are free to disclose personal information. However, it is not necessary in order to navigate the website. Joblift abides by regulatory privacy policies. This privacy policy also comprises social media and related analysis tools. The purpose of this policy statement is to fulfil the requirements for art. 13 & 14 GDPR (information obligation). This only concerns the data processing processes associated with visiting the website.

### 1\. Name and contact details of the responsible person for the data processing and the data protection officer.

This data protection related information applies for data processing by:  
Responsible for data processing:   
Lukas Erlebach, Große Reichenstraße 27, D-20457 Hamburg, Germany, e-mail: [impressum@joblift.de](mailto:impressum@joblift.de "impressum@joblift.de") Phone: +49 (0) 40 211 078 462  
Data protection officer:   
Joblift’s data protection officer, Maximilian Hartung, can be contacted via the following e-mail address: [epost@datenschutz-agentur.de](mailto:epost@datenschutz-agentur.de "epost@datenschutz-agentur.de") .

### 2\. Collection and storage of personal data and information on the purpose and type of use.

#### 1. Visit of our website

When visiting our website(s) [https://www.joblift.de](https://www.joblift.de/ "https://www.joblift.de") , [https://www.joblift.nl](https://www.joblift.nl/ "https://www.joblift.nl") , [https://www.joblift.fr](https://www.joblift.fr/ "https://www.joblift.fr") , [https://www.joblift.co.uk](https://www.joblift.co.uk/ "https://www.joblift.co.uk") , [https://www.joblift.com](https://www.joblift.com/ "https://www.joblift.com") the browser on your device automatically sends information to the server of our website. This information is temporarily stored in a so called ‘log file’.   
The following information is captured without any further action from your side. This information is saved until it is automatically deleted.   
• IP-address of the information-requesting computer (or device)   
• Date and time of access

• Name and URL of the requested file  
• Website, from which our website is accessed (referrer-URL)  
• Browser and operating system of your computer (or device)  
• Name of access-providers  
The listed information is processed for the following reasons:  
• Ensuring a smooth connection of the website  
• Ensuring comfortable use of our website  
• Evaluation of system security and stability as well as…  
• for other administrative purposes.  
The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 S.1 lit. f GDPR. Our legitimate interest follows from the purposes listed above for data collection. Under no circumstances do we use the data collected for the purpose of drawing conclusions about you personally.  
In addition, we use cookies and analysis services when you visit our website. You will find more detailed explanations under sections 4 and 5 of this data protection declaration.

#### 2. When registering for our newsletter

If you have expressly consented according to Art. 6 section 1 s. 1 a GDPR, we will use your e-mail address to send you our newsletter on a regular basis. To receive the newsletter it is sufficient to provide an e-mail address.  
You can unsubscribe at any time, for example via a link at the end of each newsletter. Alternatively, you can send your unsubscription request at any time to [privacy@joblift.com](mailto:privacy@joblift.com "privacy@joblift.com") by e-mail.

#### 3. When using our contact form

If you have any questions, we offer you the opportunity to contact us via mail ([privacy@joblift.com](mailto:privacy@joblift.com "privacy@joblift.com")). A valid e-mail address is required so that we know who sent the request and can respond to it. Further information can be provided voluntarily.  
The data will be processed for the purpose of contacting us in accordance with Art. 6 section 1 s. 1 lit. a GDPR on the basis of your voluntary consent.  
The personal data collected by us will be automatically deleted after your request has been processed.

### 3\. Information disclosure

Your personal data will not be transmitted to third parties for purposes other than those listed below.   
We will only pass on your personal data to third parties if…   
• you have given your express consent pursuant to Art. 6 section 1 s. 1 lit. a GDPR,   
• the disclosure pursuant to Art. 6 section 1 s. 1 f GDPR is necessary to assert, exercise or defend legal claims and there is no reason to assume that you have an overriding interest worthy of protection in not disclosing your data,   
• there is a legal obligation for the transfer pursuant to Art. 6 section 1 s. 1 lit. c GDPR, and   
• this is legally permissible and necessary for the processing of contractual relationships with you pursuant to Art. 6 section 1 s. 1 lit. b GDPR.

### 4\. Cookies

We use cookies on our site. These are small files that your browser automatically creates and that are stored on your device (laptop, tablet, smartphone, etc.) when you visit our site. Cookies do no damage to your end device, do not contain viruses, trojans or other malware.   
Information is stored in the cookie that results in each case in connection with the specifically used terminal device. However, this does not mean that we immediately become aware of your identity.   
The use of cookies serves on the one hand to make the use of our offer more pleasant for you. For example, we use so-called session cookies to recognize that you have already visited individual pages of our website. These will be deleted automatically after leaving our site.   
In addition, we also use temporary cookies that are stored on your end device for a specific time period to optimize user-friendliness. If you visit our site again to use our services, it will automatically recognize that you have already been with us and what entries and settings you have made so that you do not have to enter them again.   
On the other hand, we use cookies to statistically record the use of our website and to evaluate it for you amid the goal to optimise our services for you (see Section 5). These cookies enable us to automatically recognize when you return to our site that you have already been with us. These cookies are automatically deleted after a defined time period.   
The data processed by cookies is required for the aforementioned purposes in order to protect our legitimate interests and those of third parties pursuant to Art. 6 Section 1 S. 1 lit. f GDPR.   
Most browsers automatically accept cookies. However, you can configure your browser so that no cookies are stored on your computer or a message always appears before a new cookie is created. However, the complete deactivation of cookies can lead to the fact that you cannot use all functions of our website.

### 5\. Analysis- and tracking tools

The tracking measures listed below and used by us are carried out on the basis of Art. 6 section 1 s. 1 f GDPR. With the tracking measures used, we want to ensure that our website is designed to meet requirements and is continually optimised. On the other hand, we use the tracking measures to statistically record the use of our website and to evaluate it for the purpose of optimising our offer. These interests are to be regarded as legitimate within the meaning of the aforementioned provision.   
The respective data processing purposes and data categories can be found in the corresponding tracking tools.

#### 1. Google Analytics

For the purpose of demand-oriented design and continuous optimization of our pages, we use Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (<https://www.google.com/intl/us/about/>) (1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA; hereinafter "Google"). In this context, pseudonymised user profiles are created and cookies (see point 4) are used. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website such as  
• Type and version of browser  
• Operating system in use  
• referrer-URL (previously visited page),  
• host name of the accessing computer (IP-address)  
• Time of the server request  
are transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. The information is used to evaluate the use of the website, to compile reports on the website activities and to provide further services associated with the use of the website and the Internet for the purposes of market research and demand-oriented design of these Internet pages. This information may also be transferred to third parties if this is required by law or if third parties process this data on behalf of the company. Under no circumstances will your IP address be merged with other data from Google. The IP addresses are anonymized so that an assignment is not possible (IP masking).  
You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website.  
You can also prevent the collection of data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the website (including your IP address) and the processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing a browser add-on (<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>).  
As an alternative to the browser add-on, especially for browsers on mobile devices, you can also prevent Google Analytics from collecting data by clicking on this link. An opt-out cookie is set to prevent future collection of your data when you visit this website. The opt-out cookie is only valid in this browser and only for our website and is stored on your device. If you delete the cookies in this browser, you must set the opt-out cookie again.  
Further information on data protection in connection with Google Analytics can be found in the Google Analytics Help (<https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en>).  
Data protection authorities require the conclusion of an order data processing agreement for the permissible use of Google Analytics. A template is available at <https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html> von Google.

#### 2. Google Adwords Conversion Tracking

We also use Google Conversion Tracking to statistically record and evaluate the use of our website for the purpose of optimising it for you. Google Adwords will set a cookie (see sectiongraph 4) on your computer if you have accessed our website via a Google ad.  
These cookies expire after 30 days and are not used for personal identification. If the user visits certain pages of the Adwords customer's website and the cookie has not yet expired, Google and the customer can recognize that the user has clicked on the ad and has been redirected to this page.  
Each Adwords customer receives a different cookie. Cookies cannot therefore be traced via the websites of Adwords customers. The information collected using the conversion cookie is used to generate conversion statistics for Adwords customers who have opted for conversion tracking. Adwords customers see the total number of users who clicked on their ad and were redirected to a page with a conversion tracking tag. However, you will not receive any information that personally identifies users.  
If you do not wish to participate in the tracking process, you can also reject the setting of a cookie required for this - for example using a browser setting that generally deactivates the automatic setting of cookies. You can also deactivate cookies for conversion tracking by setting your browser to block cookies from the "www.googleadservices.com" domain. Google's privacy policy for conversion tracking can be found here (<https://services.google.com/sitestats/en.html>).

#### 3. Google Tag Manager

This website uses Google Tag Manager. This service allows website tags to be managed via an interface. Google Tag Manager only implements tags. This means that no cookies are set and no personal data is recorded. Google Tag Manager triggers other tags which, in turn, may record data. However, Google Tag Manager does not access this data. If tags have been disabled at the domain or cookie level, this remains in place for all tracking tags if these are implemented with Google Tag Manager. You can find out more about Google Tag Manager by clicking the following link: <http://www.google.com/tagmanager/use-policy.html>  
In case you want to opt-out look see the description and link in 1). However please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website.

#### 4. Matomo

We use the open source software Matomo to analyze and statistically evaluate the use of the website. Cookies are used for this purpose (see section 4). The information generated by the cookie about website usage is transmitted to our servers and combined in pseudonymous user profiles. The information is used to evaluate the use of the website and to enable a demand-oriented design of our website. The information is not passed on to third parties.  
Under no circumstances will the IP address be linked to other data relating to the user. The IP addresses are anonymized so that an assignment is not possible (IP masking).  
Your visit to this website is currently recorded by Matomo Webanalyse. Click here (<https://matomo.org/privacy/>), so that your visit is no longer recorded

#### 5. Usabilla

We use the feedback service "Usabilla for Websites" from Usabilla B.V. (Netherlands) ("Usabila") to collect feedback from Users and to improve the website. When a User utilizes the feedback button, a cookie will be placed on the computer and the User's browser establishes a direct link to Usabilla's server and the User's IP address, as well as other device-related information are communicated. Further details can be found Usabilla's privacy policy under: <https://usabilla.com/privacy>

#### 6. Criteo

The Joblift website also uses the services of Criteo SA. By the use of retargeting technologies, such as Ad-IDs or Cookies Criteo can show visitors of our site our offered jobs also on Criteo partner websites, partner apps or even in emails. These targeted product recommendations are played out as personalised advertising banners. The information collected is not used to personally identify site visitors. The data collected will be used to improve and customize the offer.  
For more information about the usage and privacy policies for this product, please visit: <http://www.criteo.com/privacy>

#### 7. Facebook Pixel

This Cookie is placed by Facebook. It enables Joblift to measure, optimize and build audiences for advertising campaigns served on Facebook. It enables us to see how users move between devices when accessing our web site and Facebook, to ensure that Joblift’s Facebook advertising is seen by our users most likely to be interested in such advertising by analysing which content a user has viewed and interacted with on the Joblift web site. For further information about the Facebook Pixel please see:  
<https://en-gb.facebook.com/business/help/651294705016616>

#### 8. Taboola

Taboola uses cookies to recognize which websites you visit frequently and to show how you navigate on the Joblift website. For this purpose, device-related data and protocol data is collected and anonymized user profiles are generated. Your anonymized IP address is shared with Taboola.  
You can deactivate tracking at any time under the following link in the "User Choices" section.  
<https://www.taboola.com/privacy-policy>

#### 9. Tradetracker

Joblift uses a service provided by the Tradetracker Deutschland GmbH (“Tradetracker”) on its web pages. Tradetracker is an affiliate network, which offers affiliate marketing. The objective is to enable Joblift to advertise on third party websites via this web-based distribution system, which is paid according to a sale or click commission. Joblift provides various advertising media for this purpose, which can be used by the participants of this affiliate network.  
The operating company of Tradetracker is the Tradetracker Deutschland GmbH, Eiffestraße 426, 20537 Hamburg, Germany.  
For this, Tradetracker places a cookie, in which the affiliate partner’s identification number, a reference number of the visitor as well as the advertising media is stored. This tracking cookie does not store any personal data in the process. The storage of this data has the purpose of processing commission payments between Joblift and the affiliate partner, which takes place via Tradetracker.  
The data subject can prevent the placement of cookies on his/her computer by our website at any time by means of the appropriate setting in the web browser being used and in doing so, permanently object to the placement of cookies. Furthermore, cookies, which were already placed, can be deleted at any time via a web browser or other software. This is possible with all standard web browsers. If the data subject deactivates the placement of cookies in the web browser being used, the full range of all functions on our website or the affiliate system may not be able to be used.  
The applicable privacy policies of Tradetracker can be accessed at <https://tradetracker.com/privacy-policy/>.

#### 10. Bing Ads & Remarketing for Search

The Bing service “Bing Ads” & “Bing Remarketing for Search” is used on the Joblift website, services of the Microsoft Corporation (“Microsoft”) (Microsoft Corporation, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, WA 98052-6399, USA). The application involves the operating mode “Universal Event Tracking”. This enables allocating data, sessions and interactions to a pseudonymous user ID across multiple devices and therefore, to analyse the activities of a user across all devices.  
On behalf of the operator of this website, Microsoft will use this information, to analyse your use of the website, to compile reports on the website activities and to provide the website operator with other services associated with the use of the website and the Internet. Furthermore, these purposes constitute our legitimate interest in data processing. The legal basis for the application of Bing Ads is § 15 sec. 3 of the German Telemedia Act (TMG) or art. 6 sec. 1 lit. f of the GDPR. Sessions and campaigns are terminated after a specified period of time. By default, sessions are terminated after 30 minutes without any activity and campaigns after six months. The time limit for campaigns can be a maximum of two years. You can find more detailed information regarding the terms of use and data privacy at <https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/traffic-quality>.  
If you access one of the web pages of Joblift via a Bing advertisement, a so-called conversion cookie is stored on your end device. The conversion cookie loses its validity after thirty days and does not serve the identification of the data subject. Provided that the cookie has not yet expired, the conversion cookie is used to determine whether certain sub-pages were accessed on our website. The conversion cookie allows Joblift as well as Microsoft to determine whether a data subject, who accessed our website via a Bing Ads ad, generated revenue; i.e. made or aborted a purchase. Neither Joblift or other advertisers of Bing Ads obtain information from Microsoft, with which the data subject can be identified.  
“Cookies” are used in the process. The information created in this manner on the use of this website is transmitted to a Microsoft server, among others in the USA and stored there. In the process, the complete IP address is transmitted to a Microsoft server outside the member states of the European Union or to other states party to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. The IP address transmitted by your browser in line with Bing Ads is not consolidated with other data from Bing. Furthermore, Bing complies with the privacy policies of the “EU-U.S. Privacy Shield” agreement. Bing uses this information on behalf of Joblift to analyse the use of the website, to compile reports on website activities for Joblift and to provide other services associated with the use of the website and Internet. Bing only forwards this information to third parties if this is required by law or insofar as third parties process this data on behalf of Bing. Third-party providers, including Bing, use stored cookies to place advertisements based on the previous visits of a user to this website. Under no circumstances will Bing link your IP address to other data. The collection and storage of data can be objected to at any time effective for the future.

#### 11. Recruitics

Recruitics helps us to reach a wider audience for the jobs we offer.   
Please visit Recruitics' website to learn more about their privacy policies, possible opt-outs and security measures.   
<https://recruitics.com/privacy-policy.html>

#### 12. Spoteffects

To measure the performance of our TV advertising we use the service provider Spoteffects, which is operated by Webeffects GmbH in Munich. Spoteffects works with the Matomo software and places a cookie on your computer, which Spoteffecs can use to collect the following information:  
\- Your IP address  
\- The website you click out to   
\- The website from which you accessed our site  
\- The sub-pages that you continue to visit in our offer  
\- The duration of your visit to our website  
\- The frequency with which you visit our website  
Your IP address will be anonymized, i.e. the last digits will be made unrecognisable. It is therefore not possible to subsequently recreate the user journey for Spoteffects.  
We have signed an order processing agreement with Spoteffects to protect your information. The data collected in this way will not be passed on to third parties. It is deleted after 14 months.  
If you wish to prevent this data collection, you have the option of blocking cookies in your browser settings and deleting existing cookies. You can then visit our website anonymously.  
You can find the opt-out here: trck.spoteffects.net/analytics/  
Privacy policy: <https://www.spoteffects.com/footer/impressum/#c730>

#### 13. Belboon

On our website we use services of the German affiliate marketing network Belboon. Affiliate marketing is an Internet-based sales form that enables commercial operators of Internet sites, the so-called merchants or advertisers, to place advertising that is usually paid via click or sale commissions on third-party websites, e.g. sales partners, also called affiliates or publishers. The merchant provides, through the affiliate network, an advertising medium, e.g. an advertising banner or other suitable means of Internet advertising, which is subsequently integrated by an affiliate on their own Internet pages or promoted via other channels, such as keyword advertising or e-marketing.  
Belboon sets a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. The tracking cookie by Belboon stores no personal data. Only the identification number of the affiliate, that is, the partner mediating the potential customer, as well as the ordinal number of the visitor of a website and the clicked advertising medium are stored. The purpose of storing this data is the processing of commission payments between a merchant and affiliate, which are processed via the affiliate network, that is Belboon  
The data subject may, as stated above, prevent the setting of cookies through our website at any time by means of a corresponding adjustment of the web browser used and thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Such an adjustment to the Internet browser used would also prevent Belboon from setting a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. In addition, cookies already in use by Belboon may be deleted at any time via a web browser or other software programs.  
The applicable data protection provisions of Belboon may be retrieved under <https://www.belboon.com/en/about-us/privacy/>.

#### 14. Affilinet

On our homepage we also make use of the German affiliate marketing network Affilinet.  
Affilinet sets a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. The definition of cookies is explained above. The tracking cookie by Affilinet stores no personal data. Only the identification number of the affiliate, that is, the partner mediating the potential customer, as well as the ordinal number of the visitor of a website and the clicked advertising medium are stored. The purpose of this data storage is the processing of commission payments between a merchant and affiliate, which are processed through the affiliate network, that is Affilinet.  
The data subject may, as stated above, prevent the setting of cookies through our website at any time by means of a corresponding adjustment of the Internet browser used and, thus, permanently deny the setting of cookies. Such an adjustment to the Internet browser used would also prevent Affilinet from setting a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. In addition, cookies already in use by Affilinet may be deleted at any time via a web browser or other software programs.  
The applicable data protection provisions of Affilinet may be accessed under <https://www.affili.net/uk/footeritem/privacy-policy>.

#### 15. RTB House

On our website we make use of the technology of RTB House. This technology operates with cookies and tracking pixels and enables us to recommend you further content - either on our website or on a third party website. These recommendations by RTB House are derived from your interests and your online behaviour. The content is then automatically delivered by RTB House.   
The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website, such as browser type/version, your operating system, referrer URL (the previously visited page) and the time of the server request is transmitted to the server of RTB House and stored there.  
For more information about RTB House's privacy policy, please visit: <https://www.rtbhouse.com/privacy/>.   
You can deny the tracking of interest-based recommendations by RTB House at any time via the "Opt-out" field within RTB House's privacy policy. Please note that you must de-activate the cookie separately in each device you use to access our website. In case you opted out, RTB House will still offer you content that is tailored to your interests; however, this content will no longer be derived from your use of our website.

#### 16. Ad2Games

In order to advertise the jobs offered on the Joblift website, Joblift rents advertising space on various websites via platforms such as Ad2Games.   
Within our partnership with Ad2Games, we have integrated an external tracking pixel from Ad2Games on the Joblift website. This enables us to receive an overview of the performance of Ad2Games' advertising services.  
You can find out more about the data protection guidelines of Ad2Games here: <http://www.ad2games.com/privacy-policy/>   
If you wish to opt out of this tracking, please click on this link and follow the instructions: <http://ib.adnxs.com/optout>

#### 17. Mcanism

In order to advertise the jobs offered on the Joblift website, Joblift rents advertising space on various websites via platforms such as Mcanism.   
Within our partnership with Mcanism, we have integrated an external tracking pixel from Mcanism on the Joblift website. This enables us to receive an overview of the performance of Mcanisms' advertising services.  
You can read more about Mcanism's privacy policy here:  
<https://mcanism.com/en/datenschutz/>

#### 18. Twiago

Twiago (https://www.twiago.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Twiago is Twiago located in Köln – Gustav-Heinemann-Ufer 72b, 50968 Köln. In case you would like to prevent Twiago from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future.

Privacy policy: <http://www.twiago.com/datenschutz/>

Opt-out: <http://control.twiago.com/privacy.php>

#### 19. LinkedIn Insight Tag

We use the LinkedIn Insight Conversion Tool of LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, which allows us to obtain information about the use of our website and to present advertising content to you on other websites that is tailored to your interests. A cookie with a validity of 120 days is set in your browser, which enables LinkedIn to recognize when you visit a website. LinkedIN uses this information to create anonymous reports for us about ad activity and information about how you interact with our website.

You can deactivate the LinkedIN Insight Conversion Tool and interest-based advertising by opting out at the following link: <https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out>

If you are a LinkedIN member, click on "Opt-out on LinkedIn". Other visitors click on "Opt-out".

Further information on data protection at LinkedIn can be found here: <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy#choices-oblig>

#### 20. Global Wide Media

Globalwide Media uses cookies to track the actions of any user which we have driven to the Joblift sites. We use three types of cookies the first is an offer cookie - This is an offer specific cookie. It lives as long as the offer's click lifespan and includes the user's transaction_id and IP address for tracking conversions. The second is a hash cookie - This is a hash of the user's device/connection information. This hash is used for offer targeting. The third is the offer id - This cookie stores the offer_id of all offers that the user has converted for on our network.

You can find more details about the Privacy Policy here: <https://globalwidemedia.com/legal/privacy-policy/>  
To opt out, you can visit this page: <https://globalwidemedia.com/legal/opt-out/>

### 6\. Social Media Plug-ins

We use social plug-ins of the social networks Facebook, Twitter and Instagram on our website on the basis of Art. 6 par. 1 p. 1 lit. f GDPR in order to make our company better known. The underlying advertising purpose is to be regarded as a legitimate interest within the meaning of the GDPR. Responsibility for data protection-compliant operation must be guaranteed by the respective provider. The integration of these plug-ins by us takes place in the way of the so-called two-click method around visitors of our web page in the best possible way to protect.

#### 1. Facebook

Our website uses social media plugins from Facebook to personalize their use. For this we use the "LIKE" or "SHARE"-button. This is an offer from Facebook.  
When you access a page of our website that contains such a plugin, your browser establishes a direct connection to the Facebook servers. The content of the plugin is transmitted directly from Facebook to your browser and integrated into the website.  
By integrating the plugins, Facebook receives the information that your browser has called up the corresponding page of our website, even if you do not have a Facebook account or are not currently logged on to Facebook. This information (including your IP address) is transmitted directly from your browser to a Facebook server in the USA and stored there.  
If you are logged in to Facebook, Facebook can directly associate your visit to our website with your Facebook account. If you interact with the plugins, for example by pressing the "LIKE" or "SHARE" button, the corresponding information is also transmitted directly to a Facebook server and stored there. The information is also published on Facebook and displayed to your Facebook friends.  
Facebook may use this information for the purposes of advertising, market research and demand-oriented design of Facebook pages. To this end, Facebook creates usage, interest and relationship profiles, e.g. to evaluate your use of our website with regard to the advertisements displayed to you on Facebook, to inform other Facebook users about your activities on our website and to provide other services associated with the use of Facebook.  
If you do not want Facebook to associate the information collected through our website with your Facebook account, you must log out of Facebook before visiting our website.  
The purpose and scope of the data collection and the further processing and use of the data by Facebook as well as your rights and setting options for the protection of your privacy can be found in the data protection information (<https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>) of Facebook.

#### 2. Twitter

Our website contains plugins of the short message network of Twitter Inc. (Twitter) integrated. You can recognize the Twitter plugins (tweet button) by the Twitter logo on our site. An overview of tweet buttons can be found here [(https://about.twitter.com/resources/buttons)](https://about.twitter.com/resources/buttons "\(https://about.twitter.com/resources/buttons\)").  
When you access a page of our website that contains such a plugin, a direct connection is established between your browser and the Twitter server. Twitter receives the information that you have visited our site with your IP address. If you click the Twitter "tweet button" while logged into your Twitter account, you can link the contents of our pages on your Twitter profile. This allows Twitter to associate the visit of our pages with your user account. We would like to point out that, as the provider of the pages, we are not aware of the content of the data transmitted or how it is used by Twitter.  
If you do not want Twitter to associate your visit to our pages, please log out of your Twitter account.  
For more information, please see Twitter's privacy policy (<https://twitter.com/privacy>).

#### 3. Instagram

Our website also uses so-called Social Plugins ("Plugins") from Instagram, which is operated by Instagram LLC, 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA ("Instagram").  
The plug-ins are marked with an Instagram logo, for example in the form of an "Instagram camera".  
When you access a page of our website that contains such a plugin, your browser establishes a direct connection to Instagram's servers. Instagram transfers the content of the plugin directly to your browser and integrates it into the page. This integration informs Instagram that your browser has called up the corresponding page of our website, even if you do not have an Instagram profile or are not currently logged in to Instagram.  
This information (including your IP address) is transmitted directly from your browser to an Instagram server in the USA and stored there. If you are logged in to Instagram, Instagram can immediately associate your visit to our website with your Instagram account. If you interact with the plugins, for example by pressing the "Instagram" button, this information is also transmitted directly to an Instagram server and stored there.  
The information is also published on your Instagram account and displayed to your contacts.  
If you do not want Instagram to associate the information collected through our website directly with your Instagram account, you must log out of Instagram before visiting our website.  
Please refer to Instagram's privacy policy (<https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388>) for more information.

### 7\. Rights of Persons Concerned

You have the right:  
• to request information about your personal data processed by us in accordance with Art. 15 GDPR. In particular, you may request information about the purposes of processing, the category of personal data, the categories of recipients to whom your data have been or will be disclosed, the planned storage period, the existence of a right to rectification, deletion, restriction of processing or objection, the existence of a right of appeal, the origin of your data, if these have not been collected by us, and the existence of automated decision-making including profiling and, if applicable, meaningful information on their details;  
• in accordance with Art. 16 GDPR, to demand without delay the correction of incorrect or complete personal data stored by us;  
• to request the deletion of your personal data stored with us in accordance with Art. 17 GDPR, unless the processing is necessary to exercise the right to freedom of expression and information, to fulfil a legal obligation, for reasons of public interest or to assert, exercise or defend legal claims;  
• in accordance with Art. 18 GDPR, to restrict the processing of your personal data if you dispute the accuracy of the data, or if the processing is unlawful but you refuse to delete the data, or if we no longer need the data but you need the data to assert, exercise or defend legal claims, or if you have filed an objection to the processing in accordance with Art. 21 GDPR;  
• in accordance with Art. 20 GDPR, to receive your personal data that you have provided to us in a structured, current and machine-readable format or to request its transfer to another person responsible;  
• in accordance with Art. 7 section 3 GDPR, to revoke your consent to us at any time. As a result, we are no longer allowed to continue processing data based on this consent in the future and  
• to complain to a supervisory authority pursuant to Art. 77 GDPR. In general, you can contact the supervisory authority of either your place of residence or your workplace or of our our office.

### 8\. Right of Objection

If your personal data are processed on the basis of legitimate interests pursuant to Art. 6 section 1 s. 1 letter f GDPR, you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data pursuant to Art. 21 GDPR, provided that there are reasons for this which arise from your particular situation or the objection is directed against direct advertising. In the latter case, you have a general right of objection, which we will implement without specifying a particular situation.  
If you would like to make use of your right of withdrawal or objection, simply send an e-mail to [privacy@joblift.com](mailto:privacy@joblift.com "privacy@joblift.com").

### 9\. Data Integrity

We use the most common SSL (Secure Socket Layer) method in connection with the highest level of encryption supported by your browser. Usually this is a 256 bit encryption. If your browser does not support 256-bit encryption, we use 128-bit v3 technology instead. Whether a single page of our website is transmitted in encrypted form is indicated by the closed display of the key or lock symbol in the lower status bar of your browser.   
We also use suitable technical and organisational security measures to protect your data against accidental or intentional manipulation, partial or complete loss, destruction or unauthorised access by third parties. Our security measures are continuously improved in line with technological developments.

### 10\. Up-to-dateness and amendment of this data protection regulation

This data protection declaration is currently valid and has the status as of May 2018.  
Due to the further development of our website and offers above or due to changed legal or official requirements, it may become necessary to change this data protection declaration. These Terms of Use are available in their current form at the URL <https://joblift.com/Terms-and-conditions> (privacy information at <https://joblift.com/Privacy-policy>). Old versions are not saved.
